[柯克]舰长日志，星历5943.7
[KIRK] Captain's log, stardate 5943.7.
我们计算出贝塔奈奥比将在大约三个半小时内变成新星
We have calculated that Beta Niobe will go nova in approximately three and a half hours.
它唯一的卫星萨佩顿是一颗M级行星
Its only satellite, Sarpeidon, is a Class-M planet,
根据上次报告，那里居住着一个开化的类人物种
which, at last report, was inhabited by a civilized humanoid species.
我们的仪器显示，星球上没有任何智慧生命存在
Now our instruments show that no intelligent life remains on the planet.
我们检测到的能量源就在这栋楼里，舰长
The power source we detected is in this building, Captain.
有幸存者的迹象吗？
Any sign of survivors?
没有智能生命形式的迹象
No signs of sapient life-forms.
一个满是人的星球怎么可能就这样消失了呢？
How can a planet full of people just disappear?
如果他们知道他们的太阳正在死亡
If they knew that their sun was dying,
那可能发生任何事情包括大规模自杀
it could be anything up to mass suicide.
报告说他们没有任何太空飞行能力
Reports deny that they had any space-flight capability.
这似乎是一个档案或某种图书馆
This appears to be an archive, or library of some kind.
那么我们来对地方了
Then we're certainly in the right place
要查明发生了什么
to find out what happened,
居民在哪里以及现在是否有留下来的人
where the inhabitants are, and if there are any left now.
嗯，这很好。我们从哪里开始呢？
Well, that's fine. Where do we start?
我能帮你吗？
May I help you?
我是图书管理员
I am the librarian.
我可以帮忙吗？
May I be of assistance?
也许你可以，怎么称呼？
Perhaps you can, Mr...?
阿托兹先生
Mr. Atoz.
我承认看到你们我有点意外
I confess that I'm a little surprised to see you.
我还以为大家早就走了
I had thought that everyone had long since gone.
但这是令人愉快的意外
But the surprise is a pleasant one.
毕竟，图书馆的目的就是给人使用的
After all, a library serves no purpose unless someone is using it.
你说所有人都走了？他们去哪儿了？
You say everyone is gone? Where'd they go?
当然，这取决于个人
It depended on the individual, of course.
如果你想追踪特定的人，很抱歉
If you wish to trace a specific person, I'm sorry,
该信息是保密的
but that information is confidential.
不，不是特定的人，就是一般人
No, no particular person, just people in general.
他们去哪儿了？
Where did they go?
啊，你觉得很难选择，是这样吗？
Ah, you find it difficult to choose, is that it?
是的，选择范围太广有利也有弊
Yes, a wide range of alternatives is a mixed blessing,
但也许我可以提供帮助
but perhaps I can help.
请你们走这边好吗？
Would you step this way, please?
要我帮忙吗？
May I help you?
你可以从20,000多张拟真磁带中进行选择
You may select from more than 20,000 verisim tapes,
其中数百张是最近才添加到收藏中的
several hundred of which have only recently been added to the collection.
我相信你会在这里找到令你满意的东西
I'm sure you'll find something here that pleases you.
先生，你对什么特别感兴趣？
You, sir, what is your particular field of interest?
最近的历史呢？
What about recent history?
真的吗？噢，那太糟糕了
Really? Oh, that's too bad.
我们对最近的历史知之甚少
We have so little on recent history.
没有人需要它
There was no demand for it.
不必很全面
It doesn't have to be extensive.
只要几个问题的答案
Just the answers to a few questions.
当然可以
Of course.
服务台提供参考服务
Reference services available at the desk.
你来晚了。你去哪儿了？
You're very late. Where have you been?
你很敏捷，阿托兹先生
You're a very agile man, Mr. Atoz.
你们有多少人？
Just how many of you are there?
[柯克]宇宙，最后的边疆
[KIRK] Space, the final frontier.
这些是星舰企业号的航程
These are the voyages of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务：探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: To explore strange new worlds,
寻找新生命和新文明
to seek out new life and new civilizations,
勇踏前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
星际旅行：原初
第三季第二十三集
我们所有的 "昨天"
我们一知道发生了什么就来了
We came as soon as we knew what was happening.
原谅我，先生，这是我的错
Forgive me, sir. It is my fault.
我一定是算错了
I must have miscalculated.
我们的读数表明这里根本没有人
Our readings indicated that there was no one here at all.
我当然知道
Of course I know.
很久以前，这个星球上的每个人都被警告过新星即将到来
Everyone on this planet was warned of the coming nova long ago.
他们遵循了指示，现在安全了
They followed instructions and are now safe.
你们最好也这样做
And you had better do the same.
你说他们安全了？
Did you say they were the safe?
当然，每一个人
Absolutely. Every single one.
他们去哪儿了？
Where did they go?
当然是他们想去的地方
Wherever they wanted to go, of course.
这完全取决于个人的选择
It is strictly up to the individual's choice.
我明白了
I see.
而你亲自将星球上的所有这些人送到了安全地点？
And you personally sent all these people on the planet to safety?
对，对，对，他们都走了
Yes, yes, yes. They are all gone,
除了你们三个
except you three.
当然，我不得不将简单的任务委托给我的复制品
Of course, I had to delegate the simple tasks to my replicas.
你是真的那个吗，阿托兹先生？
You are the real one, Mr. Atoz?
当然，我是真正的阿托兹先生
Of course. I am the real Mr. Atoz.
说真的，他很真实，吉姆
As a matter of fact, he's quite real, Jim.
让我们带你去一个安全的地方
Let us take you with us to a place of safety.
不，谢谢
No, thank you.
我计划在时机成熟时和我的妻子和家人团聚
I plan to join my wife and family when the time comes.
现在，不要担心我
Now, don't be concerned about me.
想想你们自己
Think of yourselves.
我迫切地警告你
I warn you most urgently.
趁现在还不晚，赶紧逃吧
Make your escape before it's too late.
图书馆随时为你服务
The library is at your complete service.
我很乐意为你提供所有参考资料来帮助你
I will gladly supply you with all reference material to help you.
有这颗星球方方面面的历史
History of the planet is available in every detail.
只要选择你最感兴趣的
Just choose what interests you the most.
千年，世纪，天，瞬间
The millennium, the century, the date, the moment.
图书馆是你的钥匙
The library is your key.
哦！它在错误的档案里
Oh! It's in the wrong file.
你们自己选择，但请记住，你们已经很晚了
Make your own selection, but remember, you're very late.
我保证我们会尽快选择
I swear we'll choose it as quick as we can.
距离新星还有多久？
How long till nova?
3小时13分钟
3hours, 13 minutes.
先生们，这不是…
This, gentleman, is not ...
先生，我想你会在这里找到一些有趣的东西
You, sir. I think you'll find something interesting over here.
[阿托兹]嗯，如果这些都不行
[ATOZ] Now, if these won't do,
我可以给你拿另一个文件
I can bring you another file.
[电子嗡嗡声]
[ELECTRONIC HUMMING]
先生，你选好了吗？
Have you made your selection, sir?
到底要我选什么？
Exactly what is it that I'm expected to select?
我确定我说得很清楚
I'm sure I was clear.
你感兴趣的时期
The period in which you're interested.
我明白了
I see.
这是一台迷人的机器，它是什么？
This is a fascinating machine. What is it?
啊，这是间时
Ah, this is the atavachron.
一个有趣的命名
An interesting nomenclature.
它是如何工作的？我能试试吗？
How does it work? May I?
哦，不，先生，不
Oh, no, sir, no.
我必须要求你不要触摸控制装置
I must ask you not to touch the controlling mechanism.
放回并做出选择
Return and make your selection.
你选好后，我将通过间时为你做好准备
When you have chosen, I will prepare you through the atavachron.
谢谢，阿托兹先生
Thank you, Mr. Atoz.
[尖叫]
[SCREAM]
史波克，老骨头
Spock. Bones.
等等！我还没帮你准备好
Wait! I haven't prepared you.
[男人笑]
[MEN LAUGH]
你们必须准备好！
You must be prepared!
这是什么地方？
What is this place?
是的，舰长呢？
Yes, and where is the captain?
你这个肮脏的东西！让我走！
You dirty thing! Let go of me!
可恶的狐狸精！
Vile vixen!
叫你来你就来，奴隶！
Come when you are bidden, slave!
你需要学习如何发挥你的优点
You need a lesson in how to use your betters.
谁是你的主人？
Who's your master?
我是一个自由人，先生
I'm a free man, sir.
那么你需要更好的礼节，自由人
Then you want better manners, free man.
防守
Defend yourself.
[全笑]
[ALL LAUGH]
[风啸]
[WIND HOWLS]
加热这块巨石可能会提供一些暂时的热量
Heating this boulder may provide some temporary heat.
怎么了？
What's wrong?
什么东西让我的相位枪不能用了
Something's preventing my phaser from operating.
噢，谢谢你，兄弟
Oh, thank you, man.
当那个蠢蛋抓到我割他钱包的时候
I thought I'd be limbered sure
我本以为一定会被他折磨一通
when that gull caught me cutting his purse.
那是什么？你没事儿吧？
What's that? Are you all right?
哦，我把你当成伪君子了
Oh, I took you to be an angler,
但你不是我们中的一员，是吗？
but you're none of us, are ya?
好吧，对他们所有人你都不是一个好欺负的人
Well, you're a bully fine coe for all of that.
谢谢
Thank you.
你给了他们一记漂亮的下马威，那些纨绔子弟
What a handsome dish you served them, the coxcombs.
你最好和我一起去图书馆
You better come back with me to the library.
你在那里会很安全
You'll be safe there.
麦考伊医生可以治那些瘀伤
Dr. McCoy can see to those bruises.
好的，亲爱的，领路，我会跟上的
I'm game, love. Lead and I'll follow.
图书馆在哪里？
Where's library?
就在那里…
It's right over there ...
舰长呢，史波克？
Where's the captain, Spock?
我们就跟在他后面
We were right behind him.
你怎么了，兄弟？
What's with you, man?
让我们在纨绔子弟和肩部拍板出现之前离开
Let's make off before coxcombs come with shoulder clappers.
不，你还记得你第一次见我是什么时候吗？
No. Do you remember when you first saw me?
你记得我是不是通过某扇门进来的吗？
Do you remember whether I came through some kind of door?
哦，我想那个蠢蛋一定是踢到你的头了
Oh, I think the wrong gull must have kicked you in the head.
来吧，亲爱的，我认识一个不会问任何问题的吸血鬼
Come on, love. I know a leech who'll ask no questions.
不，不，它一定在这儿某个地方
No. No. It must be here someplace.
吉姆！
Jim!
吉姆，你能听到我们说话吗？
Jim, can you hear us?
老骨头？史波克？
Bones? Spock?
舰长，我们听到了你的声音，但我们看不见你
Captain, we hear you, but we cannot see you.
你没事儿吧？
Are you all right?
我们一定出于某种原因错过了彼此
We must've missed each other somehow.
是的
Agreed.
显然，他们退回到过去
Apparently they've all escaped the destruction of their world
逃脱了世界的毁灭
by retreating into its past.
怜悯我们，是鬼魂
Mercy on us. It's spirits.
不，不，不，这些是我的朋友，他们是…
No, no, no. These are friends of mine, and they're ...
史波克，你在图书馆吗？
Spock, are you in the library?
实际不是
Indeed not.
我们身处北极特色的荒野
We're in a wilderness of arctic characteristics.
他的意思是很冷
He means it's cold.
你能回图书馆吗？
Can you get back to the library?
没有图书馆，舰长
There is no library, Captain.
至少我们没有看到
At least not that we can see.
我们在冰崖的底部
We're at the base of an ice cliff.
说说
Explain.
舰长,就在你消失之前
Just before you disappeared, Captain,
我发现了一台阿托兹先生称之为间时的机器
I discovered a machine which Mr. Atoz called the atavachron.
它一定以某种方式绑定了磁带查看器
It must have been tied into the tape viewer somehow.
打开通往过去的时间传送门
Opening time portals to the past.
就进入了你正在查看的时期
You cross through into the period which you were viewing.
我在查看关于他们冰河时代的资料
I was looking over some material about their Ice Age.
我在这里显然是因为
I am here, evidently, because
我和麦考伊医生跨入了同一个时刻
I stepped through at the same instant as Doctor McCoy.
是的…
Yes...
[脚步声]
[FOOTSTEPS]
我的朋友们带着增援回来了
My friends are coming back with reinforcements.
她的同伙，逮捕他
There's the mort's accomplice. Arrest him.
我们就是法律，现在要求你们伏法
We are the law, and do require that you yield to us.
什么罪名？
On what charge?
偷窃和割皮包
Thievery and purse cutting.
那是误会，我不是小偷
That's a mistake. I'm no thief.
发生了什么？
What's happening?
主啊，帮助我们，那是什么？
Lord help us. What's that?
这是鬼魂
It's spirits.
走吧，走吧，鬼魂，让诚实的人靠近
Away. Away, spirit, and let honest men approach.
继续说话！
Keep talking!
舰长！
Captain!
他们按照他的吩咐说话
They speak at his bidding.
让他闭嘴，他们就会安静
Stop his mouth and they'll quiet.
你必须靠近传送门
You must be close to the portal.
现在继续说！
Keep talking now!
吉姆，怎么了？
Jim, what's the matter?
吉姆听起来好像遇到了麻烦
Jim sounded like he was in trouble.
我们自己可能有麻烦了
We may be in trouble ourselves.
我们必须找到避难所
We must find shelter.
在这种严寒中，我们活不了太久
In this severe cold, we cannot survive much longer.
把我留在这儿，史波克
Leave me here, Spock.
我们一起走否则就停下
We go together or not at all.
别傻了
Don't be a fool.
我的手和脸都冻伤了，我感觉不到我的脚
My hands and face are frostbitten, I can't feel my feet.
一个人你有机会
Alone you have a chance.
照我说的做，去找吉姆
Now do what I say. Go try to find Jim.
我们一起去！
We go together!
你这个固执，厚脸皮的瓦肯人！
You stubborn, thick-headed Vulcan!
他正因你们的恶劣天气而受苦
He is suffering from the severity of your weather.
不幸的是，他是医生，不是我
Unfortunately, he is the doctor, not I.
我会避免在这个时候给他任何药物
I'll avoid giving him any medication at this time.
或许，要是让他保持安静和温暖，他能自然而然地恢复
Perhaps, if he's kept quiet and warm, he may recover naturally.
这里温暖宜人
It is agreeably warm here.
你叫什么？
What are you called?
我叫史波克
I'm called Spock.
连你的名字都很奇怪
Even your name is strange.
原谅我，我从没见过长得像你这样的人
Forgive me. I've never seen anyone who looks like you.
你们为什么在这？
Why are you here?
你们也是囚犯吗？
Are you prisoners too?
囚犯？
Prisoners?
这是佐尔·汗想想让某人消失时
This is one of the places Zor Kahn sends people
送他们去的地方之一
when he wants them to disappear.
你不是通过时间传送门来的吗？
Didn't you come in through the time portal?
是的，我们通过时间传送门过来，但不是作为囚犯
Yes, we came through the time portal, but not as prisoners.
我们无意中被送到了这里
We were sent here by mistake.
间时很远
The atavachron is far away,
但我认为你来自更远的某个地方
but I think you come from someplace farther than that.
没错，我根本不是来自你所知道的世界
That is true. I am not from the world you know at all.
我的家乡是数百万光年之外的一颗行星
My home is a planet millions of light years away.
哦，多么美妙！
Oh, how wonderful!
我一直很喜欢关于这种可能性的书
I've always loved books about such possibilities.
但它们只是故事
But they're only stories.
这不是真的
This isn't real.
这一切一定都是我的想象
I must be imagining all this.
我要疯了！[呜咽]
I'm going mad! [SOBS]
听我说，我坚信我确实存在
Listen to me. I am firmly convinced that I do exist.
我是真实的
I am substantial.
不是你的想象
You are not imagining this.
哦，我已经在这里很久了，一个人
Oh, I've been here for so long, alone.
当我看到你在外面时
When I saw you out there,
我不敢相信
I couldn't believe it.
他要死了吗？
Is he dying?
这是死神
Here. There's the mort.
还有死神的追随者
And there's the mort's henchman.
打开
Open up.
叫醒他
Rouse him.
你是与鬼魂交谈的小偷
You are the thief who talks to spirits.
不，我是陌生人
No. I'm a stranger.
你从哪来？
Where are you from?
一座岛屿
An island.
什么岛？
What is this island?
它被称为地球
It's called Earth.
我不知道地球岛
I know no island Earth.
没关系，继续说
No matter. Continue.
今晚之前我从未见过那个女人
I never saw that woman before tonight.
当她尖叫时
When she screamed,
据我所知，她正受到攻击
as far as I could tell, she was being attacked.
那你否认是她的同谋？
Then you deny being her accomplice?
是的，我否认
Yes, I deny it.
当我听到她的尖叫声时，我正在图书馆阅读
I was reading in the library when I heard her scream.
大人，图书馆？
My lord, the library?
你记得图书馆在哪里吗，大人？
Do you remember where the library is, my lord?
也许你在这件事中是无辜的
Perhaps your part in this is innocent.
我相信你是一个诚实的人
I believe you to be an honest man.
他是个巫师！
He's a witch!
小心，女人，我确信你有罪
Take care, woman. I'm convinced of your guilt.
不要用虚假的指控加重罪行
Do not compound it with false accusation.
他对看不见的鬼魂说话
He speaks to unseen spirits.
他是个巫师
He's a witch.
你听到了声音！
You heard the voices!
是真的，大人
It's truth, my lord.
我听到鬼魂和他说话
I heard the spirit talk to him.
他回答并叫它老骨头
He answered and did call it Bones.
你是个巫师，他施了一个咒语
You're a witch. He cast a spell.
他让我违背我的意志偷窃
He made me steal against my wish.
你肯定不会信…
Surely you don't believe...
你听过这些鬼魂吗？
You heard these spirits?
是的，大人，我可以作证
Aye, my lord. I'll witness to it.
大人，他听到的
What he heard, my lord,
只是我在图书馆墙后的朋友
were only my friends behind the wall in the library.
图书馆
In the library.
我对此一无所知
I know nothing of this.
派人去请一个精通巫术的人，让他检查一下
Send for someone learned in witchcraft and let him examine him.
这事和我没关系
I will have nothing to do with it.
大人，至少安排我见见阿托兹先生吧
My lord, at least arrange for me to meet Mr. Atoz.
我不认识阿托兹！
I know of no Atoz.
是的！是的！阿托兹！
Yes! Yes! Atoz!
我对此一无所知，对这些事一无所知！
I know nothing of this, nothing of these matters!
我不会听他说的！
I will not hear him!
让我和你说话！
Let me speak to you!
我不会听他说的！
I will not hear him!
至少让我和你谈谈！
At least let me talk to you!
巫师！巫师！巫师！
Witch! Witch! Witch!
他们会烧死你
They'll burn ya.
麦考伊，麦考伊，醒醒
McCoy. McCoy, wake up.
你是谁？
Who are you?
我叫扎拉贝斯
My name is Zarabeth.
扎拉贝斯
Zarabeth.
史波克，我们在图书馆吗？
Spock, are we in the library?
不，我们仍处于冰河时代，但目前是安全的
No, we are still in the ice age, but safe for the moment.
吉姆
Jim.
吉姆呢？
What about Jim?
医生，你的状态不能起来
Doctor, you're in no condition to get up.
你躺下休息
You lie down and rest.
我会设法找到舰长
I shall attempt to find the captain.
你找到他，史波克
You find him, Spock.
你不用担心我，只要找到他
Don't you worry about me. You just find him.
史波克？
Spock?
这个吉姆是谁？
Who is this Jim?
他是我们的指挥官，也是我们的朋友
He's our commanding officer and our friend.
我只看到你们两个，我不知道还有人
I saw only the two of you. I did not know there was another.
他没有和我们一起
He did not come with us.
他通过时间传送门被送到了另一个历史时期
He was sent through the time portal to another period in history
比这晚得多
much later than this one.
如果我要找到他
If I'm to find him,
只有一种可能的途径
there's only one possible avenue.
扎拉贝斯，你能告诉我时间传送门在哪里吗？
Zarabeth, will you show me where the time portal is?
但是你的朋友，他病了
But your friend. He is ill.
是的，没错
Yes, that is true.
如果我离开他，他有可能永远无法回到这艘船
If I leave him, there's a chance he may never regain the ship.
他会被放逐在这个时代
He would then be marooned in this time period.
但他没有死亡的危险
But he is no longer in danger of death,
所以我已经履行了对他的主要职责
so my primary duty to him has been discharged.
如果我留在这里
If I remain here,
我们队伍中的任何人都不能帮助柯克舰长
no one of our party would be able to aid Captain Kirk.
你让它听起来像一个等式
You make it sound like an equation.
它就应该是一个等式
It should be an equation.
我应该能从逻辑上解决这个问题
I should be able to resolve this problem logically.
也许它与间时有关
Perhaps it has something to do with the atavachron.
如果我对它的工作原理有更多了解就好了
If only I knew more about how it worked.
扎拉贝斯，你说你是作为囚犯被带到这里的
Zarabeth, you said that you were brought here as a prisoner.
能否问问…？
May I ask...?
为什么？
Why?
我的罪行是不明智地选择了我的亲戚
My crime was in choosing my kinsmen unwisely.
其中两人参与了谋杀佐尔·汗的阴谋
Two of them were involved in a conspiracy to kill Zor Khan.
我记得图书馆历史磁带上的那个名字
I remember that name from the history tapes in the library.
暴君佐尔·汗
Zor Kahn the tyrant.
他处决我的亲属是不够的
It was not enough that he execute my kinsmen.
佐尔·汗决心摧毁我们整个家族
Zor Kahn determined to destroy our entire family.
他使用间时把我们送到了没人能找到的地方
He used the atavachron to send us places no one could ever find us.
扎拉贝斯，我们必须回阿托兹先生和间时那里
Zarabeth, we must return to Mr. Atoz and the atavachron.
我们会带着麦考伊医生，你必须和我们一起去
We will carry Dr. McCoy and you must come with us.
我会送你和医生上船
I will send you and the doctor to the ship,
我去找柯克舰长
and I shall search for Captain Kirk.
我不能再通过传送门了
I can't go through the portal again.
如果我去了，就会死
If I do, I will die.
你不能回去？
You cannot go back?
我们谁也不能回去
None of us can go back.
当我们通过传送门时，我们被间时改变了
When we come through the portal, we are changed by the atavachron.
这就是它的功能
That is its function.
我们的基本细胞结构会根据我们进入的时间进行调整
Our basic cell structure is adjusted to the time we enter.
你不能回去
You can't go back.
如果你再次通过传送门
If you go through the portal again,
当你到达另一边时，你就会死去
you will die by the time you reach the other side.
[麦考伊]史波克？
[McCOY] Spock?
我们在哪？
Where are we?
你在这里很安全，麦考伊
You are safe here, McCoy.
是的，我记得你
Yes, I remember you.
来吧，医生，回床上
Come, Doctor. Back to bed.
你为什么还在这里，史波克？
Why are you still here, Spock?
你为什么不在找吉姆？
Why aren't you looking for Jim?
不可能去找他，医生
It is impossible to look for him, Doctor.
我们回不去了
We cannot go back.
不可能是什么意思？
What do you mean, impossible?
我们必须回去
We've got to get back.
扎拉贝斯向我解释了
Zarabeth explained it to me.
当我们通过传送门时
When we came through the portal,
它改变了我们的生理结构
it altered our physiological structure.
如果我们试图返回图书馆，我们就会死
If we attempt to return to the library, we shall die.
你是想告诉我我们被困在这里了吗？
Are you trying to tell me that we're trapped here?
是的，医生，我们被困住了
Yes, Doctor. We are trapped.
就像吉姆也被困在了他所在的地方
Just as Jim is trapped wherever he is.
[柯克]舰长日志，星历5943.9
[KIRK] Captain's log, stardate 5943.9.
这个时代的人相信巫师
The people of this time believe in witches,
我被指控会巫术
and witchcraft is what I've been accused of.
五名目击者听到麦考伊和我说话
Five witnesses heard McCoy's voice speak to me
并认为那是邪灵
and thought it was an evil spirit.
根据我对巫术审判的了解
From what I know of witchcraft trials,
我没有太多机会
I don't have much chance
除非我能找到检察官
unless I can get to the prosecutor.
没有晚餐给你，亲爱的
No supper for you, love.
来吧
Come on.
你上去吧
Up you go.
把你的杯子给我
Give me your cup.
要是喊出来，就折断你的手
Cry out and I'll break it.
别动
Don't move.
狱卒！狱卒！
Jailor! Jailor!
我被诬告了，你知道的
I'm being falsely accused. You know that.
你和我一起去宗教法庭
You will come with me before the inquisitional tribunal.
你巫术的事情将在那里得到解决
There the matter of your witchcraft will be decided.
没有巫师这种东西
There are no such things as witches.
那是亵渎
That is sacrilege.
如果他们听到你的话，他们会因为这样的想法而烧死你
If they hear you, they will burn you for such beliefs.
只有你能听懂我的话，而那是事实
You're the only one that can hear me, and that's the truth.
没有巫师，你为什么否认呢？
There are no witches. Why do you deny it?
别让他们听到你的话
Do not let them hear you.
有巫师！有！
There are witches! There are!
你自己可能会被审判官发现是巫师
You yourself may be discovered to be a witch by the inquisitor.
不！你在做什么？不！
No! What are you doing? No!
帮帮我！帮帮我！
Help! Help!
我会向审判官告发你
I'll denounce you to the inquisitor.
你来自未来，就像我一样
You came here from the future, just as I did.
所以你也是个巫师
Therefore, you, too, are a witch.
我求求你，不要牵连我
I beg you, do not implicate me.
他们会烧死我
They'd burn me.
那就帮我
Then help me.
我会尽我所能证明你是无辜的
I'll do everything I can to prove you innocent.
我将驳斥所有关于巫术的指控
I will disprove all the charges of witchcraft.
但是你绝对不能再和你身后的伙伴说话
But you must never again speak to the comrades you left behind.
帮我回图书馆
Help me return to the library.
我迷路了，我必须回到那里
I've lost my way. I must get back there.
你回不去了
You cannot get back.
我告诉你我必须回去！
I tell you I must!
我和两个朋友一起
I had two friends with me,
他们迷失在了另一个时期
who are lost in another time period.
我必须找到他们，你和我们一起回去
I must find them. You'll come back with us.
我们再也回不去了
We can never go back.
我们必须在这里，过去，度过我们的生活
We must live out our lives here in the past.
间时已经准备好我们的细胞结构和大脑模式
The atavachron has prepared our cell structure and brain patterns
让这里的生活变得自然
to make life natural here.
回到未来就意味着立即死亡
To return to the future would mean instant death.
准备？
Prepare?
我没有准备
I was not prepared.
你的阿托兹先生没有为我做任何准备
Your Mr. Atoz did not prepare me in any way.
那你必须马上回去
Then you must get back at once！
如果你没有被改变
If you were not transformed,
你在过去这里只能存活几个小时
you can only survive for a few hours here in the past.
来，快，快
Come. Hurry. Hurry.
扎拉贝斯，你是个出色的厨师
Zarabeth, you are a beautiful cook.
有人告诉过你吗？
Have you ever been told that?
最近没有
Not recently.
哦，你会发现史波克在那些事情上是非常不负责任的
Oh, well, you'll find that Spock is quite delinquent in those matters.
我没有注意到
I hadn't noticed it.
哦？
Oh?
现在我感觉好多了
Well, now that I'm feeling better,
你会注意到我们的方法有明显的不同
you'll notice a distinct difference in our approach.
真的吗？
Really?
这是值得期待的事情
It's something to look forward to.
医生，你一定足够健康
I think you must be well enough, Doctor,
能品尝这种气候所提供的几种美味了
to try the few delicacies this climate has to offer.
不，还没有
No, not yet.
以你的进步速度，很快就行了，我能看出来
At your rate of progress, it will be soon, I can see.
麦考伊医生正的进展非常快速
Doctor McCoy is making excellent progress.
史波克先生一直在无证行医
And Mr. Spock has been practicing medicine without a license.
不要让他医治你，我是这里的医生
Don't let him doctor you. I'm the doctor.
并且被认为是企业号全体船员中最糟糕的病人
And known as the worst patient in the entire crew of the Enterprise.
我想知道她在哪里
I wonder where she is.
5,000年后的未来
5,000 years in the future.
谢谢
Thank you.
我想知道吉姆在哪里
I wonder where Jim is.
谁知道呢
Who knows.
我们只能希望他一切安好，无论他在哪里
We can only hope that he is well, wherever he is.
我们只能希望是什么意思？
What do you mean, we can only hope?
你没有做点什么吗？
Haven't you done anything about it?
可以做什么？
What was there to do?
找到传送门，不会太远
Locate the portal. It can't be too far.
我们已经谈过这些了，医生
We've been through all that, Doctor.
重提这个话题有什么意义呢？
What's the point of rehashing that subject?
我们回不去了，你不明白吗？
We can't get back. Wasn't that clear to you?
是的，我很明白
Yes, that was clear to me.
那也许是你病得太重了，无法理解“回不去”的意思
Then perhaps you were too ill to understand what "can't get back" means.
我不相信，史波克
I don't believe it, Spock.
放弃尝试不像你会做的事情
It's just not like you to give up trying.
那我再给你重复一遍
Then I'll repeat it for you.
记在你的脑子里
Get this through your head.
我们回不去了
We can't get back.
这意味着我们被困在这里
That means we're trapped here,
在这个星球的过去，就像我们现在一样
in this planet's past, just as we are.
我们将在此度过余生
And we'll stay here for the rest of our lives.
现在你明白了吗？
Now do you understand?
是的，我明白了
Yes, I understand.
我从没想过我会听到这个，但我明白了
I never thought I'd hear it, but I understand.
你想留在这里
You want to stay here.
事实上，你非常有理由留在这个孤独凄凉的荒野
As a matter of fact, you're highly motivated to stay in this forsaken waste.
那个愿景刚才对你来说似乎很有吸引力
The prospect appeared quite attractive to you a moment ago.
现在，你听我说，你这个尖耳朵的瓦肯人…
Now, you listen to me, you pointed-eared Vulcan...
我不喜欢
I don't like that.
我认为我从来没喜欢过，现在我很确定
I don't think I ever did and now I'm sure.
你怎么了，史波克？
What's happening to you, Spock?
没有什么事情是不应该在很久以前发生的
Nothing that shouldn't have happened long ago.
很久以前…
Long ago...
当然，很久以前
Of course. Long ago.
这就是那个地方
This is where it is.
我不记得确切的地点了
I can't remember the exact spot.
在那，那就是传送门
That's it. That is the portal.
我不能再等了
I cannot wait any longer.
史波克？麦考伊？
Spock? McCoy?
柯克呼叫企业号，请回答
Kirk to Enterprise. Come in.
我是斯科特，舰长
Scott here, Captain.
还有多久太阳会爆炸？
How much time before the sun blows up?
17分钟，你们三个最好马上回来
17 minutes. You three had better come back right away.
我们不能，斯科提，史波克和麦考伊失踪了
We can't, Scotty. Spock and McCoy are missing.
我就知道有麻烦
I knew there was trouble.
我已经让一个登陆小队待命了
I've got a landing party standing by.
不，任何情况下
No. Under no circumstances
没有我的命令都不要派人到这里来
send anyone else here without my orders.
准备以曲速离开，通话完毕
Prepare to warp out and stand by. Kirk out.
阿托兹先生，你在哪里？
Mr. Atoz, where are you?
我可以帮你吗？
May I help you?
是你，你很幸运你找到了回到这里的路
It's you. You're lucky you found your way back here.
让我通过间时处理你
Now let me process you through the atavachron.
不
No.
阿托兹先生，我和我的朋友们来自另一个星球
Mr. Atoz, my friends and I are from another planet.
我们不属于你们的历史
We don't belong in your history.
我们根本不属于你们的星球
We don't belong on your planet at all.
就让我来处理你，让你回到属于你的地方
Just let me take care of you and get you back where you belong.
不
No.
我想找到他们之前正在查看的确切光盘
I want to find the exact disc that they were viewing.
请你回去
Please, go back.
对不起，阿托兹先生
I'm sorry, Mr. Atoz.
- 拜托  - 阿托兹先生！
-Please.  - Mr. Atoz!
我必须准备逃跑
I must prepare to escape.
我一会就放你出去
I'll let you out in a minute.
还在玩你的复制品小游戏吗？
Still up to your little game of replicas?
这次是哪个，是真的还是假的？
Which are you this time, real or not?
你显然是一个有自杀倾向的疯子
You are evidently a suicidal maniac.
我不明白你想做什么
I don't understand what you're trying to do,
但如果你继续，我们都会死
but if you continue, both of us will die,
而我不想死
and I for one, do not wish death.
如果你帮我，我们就不会死
If you help me, we won't die.
我向你承诺
I promise you that.
我不信任你
I don't trust you.
你现在是哪一个，复制品还是真的？
Which one are you now, the replica or the real one?
我是真正的阿托斯
I'm the real Atoz.
你已经拿走了我的复制品
You've done away with my replicas.
我后悔我现在必须做的事情
I regret what I must now do.
你不是真的想伤害我，对吗？
You don't really want to hurt me, do you?
你一直在试图挽救我的生命，我知道
You've been trying to save my life. I realise that.
把那东西收起来
Put that thing away.
我不能假装对你在这里感到难过
I cannot pretend to be sorry that you are here,
尽管我意识到这对你来说是个不幸
though I realise it is a misfortune for you.
我在这里也违背了我的意志，就像你一样
I'm here against my will too, just as you are.
抱歉，我不知道有什么办法让你回到你自己的时间
I'm sorry. I know of no way to return you to your own time.
我并不想回去
It's not that I wish to return.
这就是我的时间
This is my time now.
我不得不面对现实
I've had to face that.
但这里一直很孤独
But it has been lonely here.
你知道一个人是什么感觉吗？
Do you know what it's like to be alone?
真的是一个人？
Really alone?
是的，我知道是什么感觉
Yes. I know what it is like.
我相信你知道
I believe you do.
吃点东西吧，拜托
Have something to eat, please.
如果你喜欢的话
If it pleases you.
这是动物肉？
This is animal flesh?
恐怕这附近没什么可吃的了
There's not much else to eat around here, I'm afraid.
当然，因为气候
Naturally, because of the climate.
避难所的热量来源是什么？
What is the source of heat in the shelter?
有一个地下热泉
There's an underground hot spring.
好极了，那就有可能建造一个温室
Excellent. Then it will be possible to build a greenhouse of sorts.
同时，这将不得不作为唯一的营养来源
Meanwhile, this will have to do as the only source of nourishment.
这里没什么可享受的东西
There aren't many luxuries around here.
佐尔·汗只给我留下了生存所必需的东西
Zor Kahn only left me what was necessary to survive.
但他显然打算让你继续活下去
But he evidently intended that you continue living.
是的，他给了我武器、避难所、食物，生活所需的一切
Yes. He gave me weapons, a shelter, food. Everything I needed to live
除了陪伴
Except companionship.
他不希望有人说他杀了我
He did not want it said that he had me killed.
但是把我一个人送到这里
But to send me here alone,
如果这不都算杀人，那什么算？
if that is not death, what is?
非常有创意的头脑，那个人
A very inventive mind, that man.
却麻木不仁，将如此美丽的女子送去流放
But insensitive, to send such a beautiful woman into exile.
寒冷对我的影响一定比我意识到的要大
The cold must have affected me more than I realized.
请不要在意，我本来不是这样的
Please, pay no attention. I'm not myself.
我行为很可耻
I'm behaving disgracefully.
我吃了动物肉，而且我很享受
I have eaten animal flesh and I've enjoyed it.
我是怎么了？
What is wrong with me?
我和你说你很漂亮
I tell you you're beautiful.
但你确实很漂亮
But you are beautiful.
这么对你说你有错吗？
Is it so wrong to tell you so?
我一直等着听你这么说
I have longed to hear you say it.
你很美丽
You are beautiful.
比我所知道的任何美梦都更美
More beautiful than any dream of beauty I've ever known.
就待在原地，先生
Just stay where you are, sir.
我会看着你到达安全的地方
I'll see you get to safety.
现在，你要帮我找我的朋友
Now, you're going to help me look for my friends.
你真是一个坚定的人
You're a most determined man.
[通讯器发出哔哔声]
[COMMUNICATOR BLEEPS]
我是柯克
Kirk here.
[斯科特]发生什么了？你为什么要等？
[SCOTT] What's happening? Why are you waiting?
没时间解释了，你准备好曲速离开了吗？
No time to explain. Are you ready to warp out?
是的，长官
Aye, Captain.
准备传送我们上去
Stand by to beam us up.
但要是那颗恒星爆炸，不要等待
But when that star explodes, don't wait.
快点离开，通话完毕
Get out fast. Kirk out.
现在，我们要开始寻找
Now we're going to start looking.
他们在冰冻的荒野中
They were in a frozen waste.
我能听到风声
I could hear the wind.
好的，好的
All right. All right.
那一定是5000年前萨佩顿的冰河时代
It must be the Sarpeidon Ice Age, 5,000 years ago.
让我看看
Let me look.
我们一起看，阿托兹先生
We'll both look, Mr. Atoz.
史波克
Spock.
你对我不诚实，史波克
You've been dishonest with me, Spock,
对你来说这也是新鲜事
and that is also something new for you.
我已经告诉你事实了，医生
I've given you the facts, Doctor.
你所知道的事实
The facts as you know them.
还是你只是接受了扎拉贝斯的说法
Or did you just accept Zarabeth's word
因为那是你想相信的？
because it's what you wanted to believe?
告诉你的就是真相
You were told the truth.
如果扎拉贝斯是消息源，那有什么区别？
If Zarabeth is the source, what's the difference?
扎拉贝斯是一个注定要过着可怕的孤独生活的女人
Zarabeth is a woman condemned to a terrible life of loneliness.
她愿意对任何人做任何事来改变这一点
She would do anything to change that.
不是吗，扎拉贝斯？
Wouldn't you, Zarabeth?
我把我知道的都告诉了你
I told you what I know.
是吗？
Did you?
你说我们回不去了
You said we can't get back.
事实是你回不去了
The truth is you can't get back.
她不会危及其他人的生命
She would not jeopardize other lives.
她愿意做任何事来阻止那种孤独的生活
She would do anything to prevent that life of loneliness.
她会说谎，她会作弊
She would lie. She would cheat.
她甚至会谋杀我
She would even murder me,
舰长，企业号的全体船员
the captain, the entire crew of the Enterprise,
让你和她在一起在这里
to keep you here with her.
说吧，扎拉贝斯，告诉史波克真相
Go ahead, Zarabeth. Tell Spock the truth.
说啊
Go ahead.
告诉史波克你会杀人！
Tell Spock you would kill!
你要对她做什么？
What are you doing to her?
你是想杀了我吗，史波克？
Are you trying to kill me, Spock?
这真的是你想要的吗？
Is that what you really want?
想想！你有什么感觉？
Think! What are you feeling?
愤怒？妒忌？
Rage? Jealousy?
你以前有过这些感觉吗？
Have you ever had those feelings before?
这是不可能的，不可能
This is impossible. Impossible.
我是瓦肯人
I'm a Vulcan.
你认识的瓦肯人在未来的5000年后才出现
The Vulcan you knew won't exist for another 5,000 years.
想想吧，兄弟，此时此刻你们的星球上正在发生什么？
Think, man. What's happening on your planet right now, this very moment?
我的祖先是野蛮人
My ancestors are barbarians.
好战的野蛮人
Warlike barbarians.
他们几乎用自己的激情杀死了自己
Who nearly killed themselves off with their own passions.
史波克，你正在退化成你的祖先
Spock, you're reverting into your ancestors
在你出生前5000年！
5,000 years before you were born!
我已经迷失了自己
I've lost myself.
我不知道我是谁
I do not know who I am.
我们可以回去吗？
Can we go back?
我不知道
I don't know.
我只知道我回不去了
I only know that I can't go back.
我知道我会尝试，史波克
I know I'm going to try, Spock,
因为我的生活在那里
because my life is back there.
而我想要那样的生活
And I want that life.
你觉得那是对的吗？
Do you think that's the right one?
我不知道
I don't know.
如果我们要设置通往正确时期的传送门，你必须得具体
If we're to get the portal set for the proper time period, you must be specific.
我没看到
I didn't see it.
试着喊一下
Try calling out.
老骨头？史波克！麦考伊！
Bones? Spock! McCoy!
你找错了
You've got the wrong one.
拜托，时间不多了，让我走
Please, there's no time left. Let me go.
再试一次
Try again.
这里没有传送门，医生，没有希望了
There's no portal here, Doctor. It's hopeless.
我想你是对的
I suppose you're right.
你病得太厉害了，不能再待在这里了，放弃吧
You're too ill to remain out here. Give it up.
老骨头，史波克！
Bones. Spock!
是吉姆，我们来了，吉姆！
It's Jim. Here we are, Jim!
我找到了他们
I've found them.
你还能听到我说话吗？
Can you still hear me?
我们听得一清二楚，舰长！
We hear you perfectly, Captain!
跟着我的声音！
Follow my voice!
史波克，麦考伊，跟着我的声音
Spock, McCoy, follow my voice.
你们听到我了吗？继续跟着我的声音
Do you hear me? Keep following my voice.
史波克，麦考伊
Spock. McCoy.
一定是这里
This must be it.
你们在等什么？快点
What are you waiting for? Hurry.
走吧，史波克！
Come on, Spock!
你先走，医生！
You start ahead, Doctor!
我不想和你分开
I do not wish to part from you.
我不能去，如果我回去，我会死
I cannot come. If I go back, I will die.
你在等什么？快点！
What are you waiting for? Hurry!
我们有多少时间？
How much time do we have?
斯科提，还有多少时间？
Scotty, how much time is there?
你们现在就得上船
You've got to come aboard now.
出问题了
Something's wrong.
怎么了？为什么他通不过？
What's the matter? Why can't he get through?
我不知道
I don't know.
除非，是因为他们原本是一起通过传送门的
Unless, it's because they originally went through the portal together.
史波克，麦考伊
Spock, McCoy,
除非你们同时回来，否则你无法通过
you can't get through unless you both come back at the same time.
斯科提
Scotty
不管有没有命令，我要先把你传送上来
Orders or no, I'm beaming you up first.
不！等等！
No! Wait!
史波克，麦考伊，快点穿过传送门！时间不多了！
Spock, McCoy, hurry through the portal! Time is running out!
他已经计划好了逃跑，我很高兴他做到了
He had his escape planned. I'm glad he made it.
柯克呼叫企业号
Kirk to Enterprise.
没有必要再观察我了，医生
There's no further need to observe me, Doctor.
正如你所看到的，我在各个方面都回到了现在
As you can see, I've returned to the present in every sense.
但它确实发生过，史波克
But it did happen, Spock.
是的，它发生过
Yes, it happened.
但那是5000年前的事了
But that was 5,000 years ago.
而她现在已经死了
And she is dead now.
很久以前就死了，入土了
Dead and buried. Long ago.
斯科提，你在吗？
Scotty, are you there?
再不走来不及了，舰长
It's now or never, Captain.
传送我们上船
Beam us aboard
我们一旦到达就进入最大曲速，通话完毕
and go to maximum warp as soon as we're there. Kirk out.